Finding Aid for the Corinne Seeds Documentation Project LSC.1419
UCLA Library Special Collections
Corinne Seeds Documentation Project records
circa 1925-1958
UCLA Library Special Collections
Corinne Seeds Documentation Project
LSC.1419
1 unknown (1 oversize box)
Corinne Seeds (1889-1969)was the principal of the Training School of the University of California, Southern Branch (1925). In 1929, the school was renamed the University Elementary School (UES), and in the late 1940s, the school moved to the UCLA campus with the first permanent UES buildings opening in 1950. She retired in 1957. In 1982, the school was renamed the Corinne A. Seeds University Elementary School in her honor. The collection consists of biographical and historical materials, scrapbooks, sample units of work, publications and studies, and photographs relating to Seeds' work at the UCLA University Elementary School.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Florence Itkin, 1984.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942329103606533
Biography
Seeds was born in 1889; in 1925, she became principal of the Training School of the fledgling University of California, Southern Branch, located on North Vermont Ave. in Los Angeles; in 1929, Seeds and the Training School moved to its first Westwood location on Warner Ave., and the school was renamed the University Elementary School (UES); in the late 1940s the school moved to the UCLA campus, and the first permanent UES buildings opened in 1950; Seeds retired as principal of UES in 1957; she died in 1969; in 1982, the school was renamed the Corinne A. Seeds University Elementary School in her honor.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of biographical and historical materials, scrapbooks, sample units of work, publications and studies, and photographs relating to Corinne Seeds and her work at the UCLA University Elementary School.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Biography of Corinne Seeds.
History of UCLA University Elementary School (UES).
Family School Alliance Scrapbook, 1917-1957.
Sample units of work from UES classes.
Publications and studies related to Seeds' program.
Outdoor education.
Photographs.
Related Material
Corinne Seeds Papers (Collection 838). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
UES: the history of the creative elementary school[oral history transcript] / Corinne Seeds, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1963. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Elementary school principals -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Corinne Seeds Documentation Project--Archives.; Seeds, Corinne A. (Corinne Aldine); UCLA Lab School
- History of Miss Seeds, "Box I." (Box 1)
- History of University Elementary School during Miss Seeds' administration., "Box II.", 1925-1957 (Box 2)
- Family School Alliance Scrapbook., 1917-1957. (Box 3)
- Summer Demonstration School. Daily record of The Westwood Movement, 5th Grade, Nora Heflin, teacher., 1939. (Box 4)
- Summer Demonstration School. Daily record of The Study of Trains, 4th Grade, Mildred Frazee, teacher., 1940. (Box 5)
- Study of The Inca People, 6th Grade, Gertrude Maloney, supervising teacher., Spring 1942. (Box 6)
- Units-of-work. Social Studies Sequences, Kindergarten through 6th Grade. "Box IV." (Box 7)
- Teacher-prepared information relating to the Units-of-Work. (Box 8)
- "Harbor box": a unit of study as part of transportation in the community, Grade 1. (Box 9)
- "Westward Movement Box": a 5th Grade unit of work. (Box 10)
- Publication and studies related to Miss Seed's program (doctoral and master's theses) "Box V." (Box 11)
- Publications and studies related to Miss Seeds' program, "Box V." (Box 12)
- Outdoor education. Diana Anderson, PhysdicalEducation Suervisor., 1952-1955. (Box 13)
- Outdoor education. Diane Anderson., 1956-1958. (Box 14)
- Photographs of School program. (Box 15)
- Photograph albums. (Box 16, Box 17)